In this video, you see me dressed in this reflective suit and our camera system is scanning the wall at a rate of four times every second. The suit is reflective, so we can actually capture enough photons that we can see where I am and what I'm doing, without the camera actually directly imaging me. By capturing photons that scatter from the wall to my tracksuit, back to the wall and back to the camera, we can capture this indirect video in real time. And we think that this type of practical non-line-of-sight imaging could be useful for applications including for self-driving cars, but also for biomedical imaging, where we need to see into the tiny structures of the body. And perhaps we could also put similar camera systems on the robots that we send to explore other planets. Now you may have heard about seeing around corners before, but what I showed you today would have been impossible just two years ago. For example, we can now image large, room-sized hidden scenes outdoors and at real-time rates, and we've made significant advancements towards making this a practical technology that you could actually see on a car someday. But of course, there's still challenges remaining. For example, can we image hidden scenes at long distances where we're collecting very, very few photons, with lasers that are low-power and that are eye-safe. Or can we create images from photons
En este video, me ven con un traje reflectivo y nuestro sistema de cámaras escanea la pared a un ritmo de cuatro veces por segundo. El traje es reflectivo así que podemos capturar los fotones necesarios para determinar dónde estoy y qué estoy haciendo sin que la cámara me enfoque de forma directa. Al capturar los fotones que se dispersan desde la pared hacia mi traje, de regreso a la pared y nuevamente hacia la cámara, podemos capturar este video "indirecto" en tiempo real. Creemos que este tipo de escaneo no lineal puede ser útil en distintas aplicaciones: en los vehículos autónomos pero también en las bioimágenes, donde necesitamos ver el interior de las estructuras diminutas del cuerpo. Quizá podríamos equipar con sistemas de cámaras similares a los robots que enviamos a explorar otros planetas. Tal vez ya escucharon sobre cómo mirar detrás de las esquinas, pero lo que les mostré hoy habría sido imposible hace dos años. Por ejemplo, podemos escanear enormes escenas ocultas en el exterior en tiempo real, y hemos avanzado bastante en conseguir que esta tecnología pueda efectivamente detectar un automóvil en el futuro. Pero por supuesto, aún hay desafíos que superar. Por ejemplo, ¿podemos escanear escenas ocultas a larga distancia, en cuyo caso se recolectan muy pocos fotones, con láseres que usen poca energía y sean seguros para la vista? ¿Podemos crear imágenes a partir de los fotones
that have scattered around many more times than just a single bounce around the corner? Can we take our prototype system that's, well, currently large and bulky, and miniaturize it into something that could be useful for biomedical imaging or perhaps a sort of improved home-security system, or can we take this new imaging modality and use it for other applications? I think it's an exciting new technology and there could be other things that we haven't thought of yet to use it for. And so, well, a future with self-driving cars may seem distant to us now -- we're already developing the technologies that could make cars safer and more intelligent. And with the rapid pace of scientific discovery and innovation, you never know what new and exciting capabilities could be just around the corner. (Applause)
que se han dispersado muchas más veces que un único rebote detrás de la esquina? ¿Podemos tomar nuestro prototipo que es, pues, actualmente muy grande y reducir su tamaño a algo que sea útil para las bioimágenes, o para un tipo de sistema mejorado de seguridad para el hogar? ¿Podemos darle a esta nueva modalidad de escaneo de imágenes otras aplicaciones? Es una tecnología nueva emocionante y podría haber otras aplicaciones que no hemos ni imaginado aún. Así que... un futuro en el que haya vehículos autónomos puede ahora parecernos distante, pero estamos desarrollando las tecnologías que podrían hacer que los autos sean más seguros e inteligentes. Con el acelerado ritmo de los descubrimientos científicos y las innovaciones, nunca se sabe qué nuevas y emocionantes aplicaciones podríamos encontrar tras doblar la esquina. (Aplausos)